Preliminary Inventory to the Alexis V. Lapteff Papers, 1921-1971
Hoover Institution Archives
Alexis V. Lapteff Papers,
1921-1971
71016
Lapteff, Alexis V.
1 folder, 1 envelope (0.1 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, reports, and photographs, relating to relief work in the Ufa-Urals district.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1970.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
American Relief Administration.; International relief.; Soviet Union.; Russia (Federation); Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921--Civilian relief.; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
- Consolidated monthly report, ending 1923 June 1 (Box 1)
- Protection Report, based on physical inventory of food stock, 1923 April 1
- Adult Feeding Table, Corn Issue, 1922 March-September
- Document issued to Colonel Bell by the Plenipotentiary Representative of RSFSR giving him the right of direct wire communications in the region, No. 1101, 1922 May 4 (in Russian)
- Address in the form of a manuscript presented to Colonel Bell from the Russian employees of the ARA (in Russian and English)
- Letter to A. V. Lapteff by the ARA, Colonel Bell, 1923 June 25
- Photographs
  - ARA staff in front of the first ARA office in Ufa, winter of 1921-1922
  - Children and members of ARA in front of one of Ufa ARA "kitchens," 1921-1923
  - ARA Ufa office building on Pushkin Street, 1922-1923
  - Colonel Bell at his desk in Ufa office, with Messrs Howard, Murphy, and Verdon
  - Mr. La Salle, Colonel Bell, and Mr. Lykes in Ufa. Colonel Bell and Mr. Lykes wearing the tartar tibiteykas
  - Mr. Blandy in front of sleigh on Ufa street, 1922
  - Inside of children's home, somewhere in Ufa region, 1922-1923
  - Well-to-do bashkir (or a tartar?) with his two wives and children, 1923
- Photocopy of page 14 of A.R.A. Association Review, 1941 January